How do you feel about bees?
你对蜜蜂的印象如何？
Do you get irritated when they buzz around you and do you fear their mission is just to sting you?
当它们在你身边嗡嗡作响时，你会感到烦躁吗？你会担心它们的目的就是蛰你吗？
Love them or loathe them, these little insects are extremely important creatures, and without them we might starve.
无论你是喜欢还是讨厌它们，这些小小的昆虫都是极其重要的生物，没有它们，人类可能会面临饥荒。
Bees deserve some respect – they give us honey, and they play their part either pollinating the many vegetables and fruits we eat directly or pollinating the food for the animals that we then consume.
蜜蜂值得我们尊重——它们为我们酿造蜂蜜，还承担着重要的传粉工作：要么直接为我们食用的各类蔬果传粉，要么为我们饲养的动物所吃的饲料作物传粉。
In fact, they are the world’s most important pollinators.
事实上，蜜蜂是全球最重要的传粉者。
That’s not all – a study by the University of Reading in the UK, found bees and other pollinating insects have a global economic value of around £120bn ($150bn) and contribute around £690m ($850m) to the UK economy every year.
不仅如此，英国雷丁大学的一项研究发现，蜜蜂及其他传粉昆虫的全球经济价值约为1200亿英镑（合1500亿美元），每年为英国经济贡献约6.9亿英镑（合8.5亿美元）。
So, bees are worth protecting, and although a small number of bee species are vital for crops such as oilseed rape, apples and strawberries, experts say we should be taking care of all our bees.
因此，蜜蜂值得被保护。尽管只有少数几种蜜蜂对油菜、苹果、草莓这类作物的生长至关重要，但专家表示，我们应当保护所有种类的蜜蜂。
Researchers say conservation efforts should be aimed at a wide number of species – even those that currently contribute little to crop pollination – in order to maintain biodiversity and ensure future food security.
研究人员指出，为了维护生物多样性、保障未来的粮食安全，保护工作应覆盖更多的蜜蜂物种，哪怕是那些目前对农作物传粉贡献甚微的种类。
Unfortunately, in recent times, bee populations have been declining due to pesticides, parasites, disease and habitat loss.
遗憾的是，近年来由于杀虫剂的使用、寄生虫侵扰、疾病传播以及栖息地丧失等因素，蜜蜂的数量一直在减少。
It’s something we should be worried about because, as Gill Perkins, chief executive of the Bumblebee Conservation Trust, told BBC Future website: “They provide a whole ecosystem service.”
这一现象值得我们警惕，正如大黄蜂保护信托基金的首席执行官吉尔·珀金斯在接受BBC未来频道采访时所说：“蜜蜂提供着完整的生态系统服务。”
The recent lockdowns caused by the coronavirus pandemic seem to have given bee populations a little boost because they faced less human disturbance, traffic and polluting fumes.
新冠疫情期间实施的封锁措施，似乎让蜜蜂数量有了小幅回升，因为它们受到的人类干扰、交通影响以及尾气污染都有所减少。
Conservationists hope, going forward, people will appreciate bees more and encourage them to thrive as they reconnect with nature.
环保人士希望，在未来，随着人们重新亲近自然，大家能更加珍惜蜜蜂，助力它们繁衍兴旺。
Gill Perkins says, “They are beginning to realise how their mental health and wellbeing is supported by nature – particularly by bumblebees, which are so iconic and beautiful and buzzy.”
吉尔·珀金斯表示：“人们开始意识到，我们的心理健康和整体福祉都依赖于大自然——尤其是那些标志性的、美丽的、嗡嗡作响的大黄蜂。”
So, it really seems time to give bees a second chance.
所以，现在确实是时候给蜜蜂更多的关注与呵护了。